A Guide to the Papers of the Tucker, Harrison and Smith Families, 1790-1940
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Tucker, Harrison and Smith Families 1790-1940
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2589, 3825, 3847, 3847-a through 3847-h, and 3847-j through 3847-l
This collection consists of ca. 22,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Several separately accessioned collections have been interfiled because the material is so closely related. The major portion of the papers was given to the University library by Mr. Edward W. Gamble, Jr., 1817 Fendall Avenue, Charlottesville, Virginia, on July 14, 1975. This portion includes accession numbers 3825, 3847, 3847-a through 3847-f, 3847-h, and 3847-j and was originally deposited at the library by Mrs. Edward W. Gamble, Jr., between the years 1951 and 1958. Mrs. Gamble was the daughter of University of Virginia professor Charles W. Kent and Eleanor Smith. In addition, accession number 2589 was given to the library by Mrs. Gamble on January 10, 1947, and accession number 3847-k was given to the library by Mrs. Gamble on January 13, 1965.
Accession number 3847-g consists of 123 letters written to Maria Carter (Harrison) Broadus during the years 1839-1857 and was given to the library by Dr. J. Hartwell Harrison, Harvard Medical School, Department of Surgery, Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 721 Huntington Avenue, Boston, Massachusetts, 02115, on July 29, 1975. These letters were originally deposited at the library on April 6, 1954 by Mrs. Carrington Harrison, Dr. Harrison's mother. Accession number 3847-1 was a gift of Mrs. C. W. Kent on March 2, 1975 and includes ca. 100 items for the period 1837-1900, consisting of papers of Lelia Tucker and of the Smith and Harrison families.
Biographical/Historical Information
Principal correspondents during the first half of the nineteenth century include Dr. Peachey Harrison (1777-1848) of Harrisonburg, Virginia, his wife Mary Stewart Harrison (1783-1857), and their children Edward Tiffin Harrison (1805-1828), Gessner Harrison (1807-1862), Mary Jane Harrison (1816-?), Margaret Frances (Harrison) Stevens (1819-1858), Caroline Elizabeth Harrison (1822-?), and Peachey Rush Harrison (1823-1852).
Gessner Harrison was a student during the first session of the University of Virginia, graduating in 1828 in medicine and ancient languages. In 1828 he received a temporary appointment to the professorship of ancient languages at the University, succeeding George Long, and in 1829 received a permanent appointment. He served as chairman of the faculty a number of times. In 1859 he left the University to found a school of the classics in Belmont, Virginia. He married Eliza Lewis Carter Tucker, the University's first professor of moral philosophy.
George Tucker (1775-1861) was born on Bermuda and at the age of twenty came to the College of William and Mary where his cousin St. George Tucker was a law professor and where he studied law. He was elected to the Virginia General Assembly in 1815 and served three terms in the House of Representatives, 1819-1825. He was appointed to the University of Virginia faculty in 1825, a position he resigned in 1845 in order to move to Philadelphia and devote his time to literature. While at the University he served as chairman of the faculty for several terms. Tucker wrote poetry and novels, a two-volume biography of Thomas Jefferson, and a statistical work Progress of the United States in Population and wealth in Fifty Years in 1843. This collection includes the unpublished manuscript of one of his novels: A Century Hence or A Romance of 1941. Tucker married three times. In 1797 he married Mary Byrd Farley who died in 1799. In 1802 he married Maria Ball Carter, the great niece of George Washington, who died in 1823. His third wife was Louisa Bowdoin Thompson whom he married in 1828. She died in 1859. All of his children were born during his second marriage.
Gassner Harrison's daughter Mary Stuart Harrison married Francis H. Smith, still another professor at the University. Smith (1829-1928) was a student at the University from 1849-1851. He was appointed assistant to the Professor of Mathematics for 1851-1853 and was Professor of Natural Philosophy 1853-1907. He was Emeritus Professor in residence from 1907 till his death in 1928.
Smith's daughter Eleanor married Charles W. Kent (1860-1917), Professor of German and French at University of Virginia from 1888-1893 and Professor of English literature from 1893-1917. He was the first literary editor of the sixteen volume Library of Southern Literature, as well as the first editor of the University of Virginia Alumni Bulletin. Charles Kent's papers include a number of letters from Woodrow Wilson and correspondence with Kent's brother Harry T. Kent, an attorney in St. Louis, Missouri. Kent's papers relate to a number of topics about the University including the Y.M.C.A., the founding of Madison Hall, and the possibility of coeducation at the University. There is a group of letters concerning Kent's running for the State Board of Education in 1906.
Scope and Content Information
The Tucker, Harrison, and Smith papers (accession numbers 2589, 3825, 3847, 3947-a through 3847-h, and 3847-j through 3847-l) consist of nineteen linear shelf feet (ca. 22,500 items) ranging in date from 1790 through 1940. The collection consists of the correspondence and papers of members of several families linked together by marriage and in many cases connected to the University of Virginia. In addition to the correspondence, which is the major portion of the collection, there are manuscripts, including poems by George Tucker and his unpublished novel A Century Hence or A Romance of 1941, diaries including one from the Civil War period, financial records, genealogical information, student notebooks, notebooks and papers of several University of Virginia professors, wills, and a few miscellaneous papers dealing with slaves.
The correspondence, primarily among relative of the Tucker, Harrison, Smith, Kent, Lewis, Hamilton, Stevens, and Carter families, spans the entire nineteenth century and includes the correspondence of four University of Virginia professors - George Tucker, Gessner Harrison, Francis Henry Smith, and Charles William Kent. The families were, for the most part, located in Charlottesville or other areas of Virginia, but there is some correspondence with relatives in Kentucky and Ohio. Some of the correspondence mentions political issues of the day, but most of the letters concern family and personal affairs, with University life a frequent topic. The family letters discuss French lessons, boarding school, church activities, weddings, illnesses and deaths. There are letters from Gessner and Edward Tiffin Harrison describing life at the University in the first years of its existence, letters describing activities surrounding William H. McGuffey (1800-1873), who became Professor of Moral Philosophy at the University in 1845 and who is best known for his school reader, and letters discussing life in Harrisonburg, Virginia from the 1790's through the 1890's. The letters of George Tucker and his daughter Mary Lelia Tucker in the late 1840's describe life in Philadelphia. George Tucker described his travels in the South in 1860 and 1861, and Gessner Harrison's sons wrote a number of letters during the Civil War describing their experiences. There are also several letters written in the 1820's by Lieutenant Lawrence Fielding Carter who was serving in the United States Army and was stationed in Florida and the Arkansas territory.
In addition to family correspondence, there are also a number of letters from other University of Virginia professors such as William B. Rogers, Charles S. Venable, John W. Mallet, John B. Minor and Maximilian Schele De Vere, among others, as well as the first president of the University, Edwin A. Alderman.
Other notable correspondents include John Singleton Mosby, Thomas Nelson Page, and Woodrow Wilson. There are approximately twenty-five letters from Mosby, primarily to Francis H. Smith, during the years 1880- 1916. Smith was Mosby's professor at the University in the early 1850's. There is a similar number of letters from Woodrow Wilson to Charles W. Kent during the period 1880-1916. Wilson attended the University from 1879 through 1881 where he became friends with Kent. He continued to be interested in University happenings and in an 1894 letter expressed his opposition to coeducation at the University. In another letter he explained his reasons for turning down the presidency of the University of Virginia. Kent also corresponded with Thomas Nelson Page, and a few of Page's letters express his views on Southern literature.
Organization
The correspondence (boxes 1-45) has been arranged in chronological order. It is followed by manuscripts of poems and essays (boxes 45-46), diaries (boxes 46-47), genealogical material (box 47), business papers (boxes 47-50), wills (box 50), school notebooks and other papers dealing with the University of Virginia (boxes 51-54), and miscellaneous items (boxes 54-56).
The Children of Charles Carter (?-1826) and Betty (Lewis)
1. Maria Ball Carter (1784-1823) m. George Tucker (1775-1861)
2. William Farley Carter (1799- ?)
3. Eleanor Custis Lewis Carter (1800?) m. Henry Brown
4. Lawrence Fielding Carter (1803-?)
5. Otwayanna Carter (1805-?) m. ? Owens
6. George Washington Carter
The Children of George Tucker and Maria Ball Carter
1. Eleanor Rosalie Tucker (1804-1818)
2. Maria Farley Tucker (1806-1893) m. George Rives (1802- 1874)
3. Eliza Lewis Carter Tucker (1808-?) m. Gessner Harrison (1807-1862)
4. Mary Lelia Tucker (1810-?)
5. Daniel George Tucker (?- 1838)
The Children of Colonel Benjamin Harrison and Mary McClure
1. Benjamin Harrison m. Ann H[?]
2. Margaret Harrison m. ? Logan
3. Dr. Peachey Harrison (1777-1848) m. Mary Stewart Harrison(1783-1857)
The Children of Dr. Peachey Harrison include:
1. Edward Tiffin Harrison (1805- 1828)
2. Gessner Harrison (1807-1862) m. Eliza Lewis Carter Tucker (1808- ?)
Their Children:
a. Maria Carter Harrison (1831-1857) m. John A. Broadus, a Baptist clergyman
b. Mary Stuart Harrison (1834-1917) m. Francis H. Smith
c. George Tucker Harrison (1835-1925) m. (1) Lelia Bell(2)Cornelia Ostrander
d. Edward Tiffin Harrison (1837-1873)
e. Peachey Gessner Harrison (1839-193?) m. Julia Riddick
f. Charles Carter Harrison (1842-1882) m. Cornelia Rives
g. Henry William Harrison (1845-1920)
h. Eleanor Rosalie Harrison (1847-1920) m. William Mynn Thornton
i. Robert Lewis Harrison (1847- 1920) m. Marie Duncan
j. Francis Washington Harrison (b. & D. 1852)
3. Mary Jane Harrison (1816-?) 4. Margaret Frances Harrison (1819- 1858) m. William G. Stevens
a. Williette Stevens m. ? Baughman b. Frank Stevens
5. Caroline Elizabeth Harrison (1822-?)
6. Peachey Rush Harrison (1823-1852) m. Mary Rodes
a. Mary Lynn Harrison m. M. White Williamson
The Children of Daniel Grove Smith and Ellen E. (Hamilton) Smith
1. J. Howard Smith
2. Summerfield Smith
3. Edmund Buckey Smith
4. Francis H. Smith (1829-1928) m. Mary Stuart Harrison (1834-1917)
The Children of Francis H. Smith and Mary Stuart Harrison
1. Eliza L. C. (Ellie) Smith m. ? Walker
2. Lelia Smith m. Lucian H. Cocke
Their Children:
a. Francis Cocke
b. Lucian Cocke
c. ? Cocke m. William H. Goodwin
3. James Duncan Smith, became an artist
4. Rosalie M. Smith m. Carrington Harrison
Their Children:
a. Francis H. Harrison
b. Dr. J. Hartwell Harrison
c. Dr. Carrington Harrison
5. Gessner Harrison Smith
6. George Tucker Smith, became a surgeon in U.S. Navy
7. Mary Stuart Smith
8. Eleanor Smith m. (1) Fielding D. Miles
Their Child:
Elise Fielding Miles (1888-?) m. ? Buckler
m. (2) Charles W. Kent (1860- 1917)
Their Child:
Eleanor Douglas Kent (1897-1967) m. Edward W. Gamble, Jr.
Miscellaneous Family Members
1. Lucy (Stevens) Clarke - Sister of William G. Stevens
2. Mary Byrd Farley - George Tucker's first wife
3. Eliza P. Hamilton - married to one of Ellen E. (Hamilton) Smith's brothers
4. James L. Hamilton - brother of Ellen E. (Hamilton) Smith
5. Matthew Gill Hamilton - brother of Ellen E. (Hamilton) Smith
6. Harry T. Kent - brother of Charles W. Kent
7. Eleanor Parke (Custis) Lewis - married Lawrence Lewis
8. George Lewis - brother of Betty (Lewis) Carter
9. Lawrence Lewis - brother of Betty (Lewis) Carter
10. Robert Lewis - brother of Betty (Lewis) Carter
11. Alexander Smith - brother of Daniel Grove Smith and uncle of Francis H. Smith
12. Jacob R. Stevens - brother of William G. Stevens
13. Joseph M. Stevens - brother of William G. Stevens
14. Louisa Bowdoin Thompson - George Tucker's third wife
15. St. George Tucker (1752 - 1827) - George Tucker's cousin, professor of law at the College of William and Mary
16. Eliza Ridgeley (Hamilton) Uhler - daughter of Eliza P. Hamilton
Contents List
- Robert Lewis to Betty (Lewis) Carter 1790 Feb. 27, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Benjamin Harrison 1798 Jan. 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Joshua Wills to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1799 May 7, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1802-1804, 6 ALS; 3 AL (Box 1)
- Betty (Lewis) Carter to Maria Ball Tucker 1806 May 1, ALS (Box 1)
- Eliza Gibbon to Maria Ball Tucker 1809 Feb. 20, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1809 Oct. 3, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to St. George Tucker 1811 Nov. 16, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Margaret (Harrison) Logan 1812 May 14, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to St. George Tucker 1812 Aug. 22, ALS (Box 1)
- M. C. Carter to Frances Latham 1813 June 14, ALS (Box 1)
- Betty (Lewis) Carter to Maria Ball Tucker 1814 Jan. 20, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to St. George Tucker 1814 Jan. 24; Jan. 27; March 25, 3 ALS (Box 1)
- Edmund Edrington to Charles Carter 1815 Sept. 7, ALS (Box 1)
- Ann Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1815 Dec. 31, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to St. George Tucker 1816 Feb. 11, ALS (Box 1)
- Robert Lewis to [Betty Lewis Carter] 1816 April 5, Typescript (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to Eleanor Rosalie Tucker 1816 June 17, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to St. George Tucker 1816 Aug. 1, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1816 Nov. 21-Dec. 14, 3 ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1817 Jan. 2 & 10, 2 ALS (Box 1)
- Frances L. Carter to Eleanor Rosalie Tucker 1817 Feb. 25, ALS (Box 1)
- Betty (Lewis) Carter to George Lewis 1817 Dec. 14, ALS (Box 1)
- Frances Lelia Coalter to Eleanor Rosalie Tucker 1812 Jan. 2, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to Betty (Lewis) Carter 1818 Dec. 27, Typescript (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her daughter Mary Farley Tucker 1819 Sept. 4, ALS (Box 1)
- Charles Carter to his wife Betty (Lewis) Carter 1819 Nov. 15, ALS (Box 1)
- Charles Carter to his wife Betty (Lewis) Carter 1819 Nov. 18, ALS (Box 1)
- George Washington Carter to his father Charles Carter 1819 Dec. 8, ALS (Box 1)
- Charles Carter to his wife Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 Jan. 10, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her husband George Tucker 1820 Feb. 2, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 March 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her daughter Maria Farley Tucker 1820 March 11, ALS (Box 1)
- William Farley Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 April 7, ALS (Box 1)
- Maira Ball Tucker to her mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 April, ALS (Box 1)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 June 23, ALS (Box 1)
- Eleanor Parke (Custis) Lewis to her sister-in-law Betty (Lewis) Carter 1820 Nov. 23, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her husband George Tucker 1820 Dec. 3, ALS (Box 1)
- M. N. Hinton to Erasmus G. Hamilton 1821 April 12, ALS (Box 1)
- William Farley Carter to his sister Maria Ball Tucker 1821 June 17, ALS (Box 1)
- Maira Ball Tucker to her mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1821 June 25, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to his father-in-law Charles Carter 1821 Aug. 26, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to George Tucker 1821 Dec. 14, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to his wife Maria Ball Tucker [1821] Dec. 15, ALS (Box 1)
- M[aria]; B[all]; T[ucker] to George Tucker 1821 Dec. 18, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her husband George Tucker 1821 Dec. 20, ALS (Box 1)
- B[etsy]; M[ary] Douglas to Maria Farley Tucker 1821 Dec. 22, ALS (Box 1)
- M[aria]; B[all] Tucker to George Tucker [1821] Dec. 23, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to his wife Maria Ball Tucker 1821 Dec. 26, ALS (Box 1)
- Maria Ball Tucker to her husband George Tucker 1821 Dec. 27, ALS (Box 1)
- George Tucker to Eliza Lewis Carter (Tucker) Harrison 1822 Feb. 6, ALS (Box 1)
- Eleanor Parke (Custis) Lewis to her niece-in-law Maria Ball Tucker 1822 Dec. 22, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to John Baxter 1823 Jan. 11, ALS (Box 1)
- Lawrence Lewis to his brother Robert Lewis 1823 Feb. 10, ALS (Box 1)
- Peachey Harrison to John Baxter 1823 June 3?; Sept. 1, 2 File copies (Box 1)
- George Tucker to Eliza Lewis Carter (Tucker) Harrison 1823 Dec. 30, ALS (Box 1)
- William Farley Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1824 July 21, ALS (Box 1)
- John W. Stevens to Colonel B. F. Owens 1824 July 24, ALS (Box 1)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1824 Sept. 4, ALS (Box 1)
- Eliza Lewis Carter (Tucker) Harrison to her cousin Mary Byrd (Farley) Tucker 1824 Sept. 8, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Cassell Harrison 1824 Oct., ALS (Box 1)
- B. F. Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison ca. 1824, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1825 March 15, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1825 March 15, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 March 19, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 March 20, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 March 21, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to [?] 1825 March 21, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 April 9 & 18, 2 ALS (Box 1)
- Ann H. Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 April 23, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 April 30, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1825 May 19, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison [1825] May 26, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1825 May 30, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Mary Jane Harrison 1825 May 31, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to James M. Bush [1825 Spring], ALS (Box 1)
- Ann [Moore] to Gessner Harrison 1825 June 4, ALS (Box 1)
- Lawrence Lewis to his sister Betty (Lewis) Carter 1825 June 6, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1825 July 5, ALS (Box 1)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1825 July 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison 1825 July 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Otwayanna (Carter) Owens to Betty (Lewis) Carter ca. 1825 Aug. 19, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison [1825] Sept. 29, AL (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1825 Oct. 11, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1825 Oct. 20, ALS (Box 1)
- Ann Moore to Gessner Harrison 1825 July 22, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 Aug. 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison [1825 Summer], ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 Sept. 12, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary Jane and Margaret Harrison 1825 Sept. 19, ALS (Box 1)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1825 Oct. 20, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison [1825] Oct. 28, ALS (Box 1)
- Gessner Harrison to [Ann Moore] ca. 1825 [Oct.-Nov.], ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1825 Nov. 4, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1825 Nov. 12, ALS (Box 2)
- Ann Moore to Gessner Harrison 1825 Nov. 23, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1825 Dec. 9, ALS (Box 2)
- Robert Lewis to his sister Betty (Lewis) Carter 1825 Dec. 27, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to James Harrison [1825], ALS (Box 2)
- John P. Emmet to A. S. Brockenbrough 1826 Jan. 5, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1826 Jan. 16, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his brother-in-law Henry Brown 1826 Feb. 6, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Mary (Stewart) Harrison (Mrs. Peachey Harrison) 1826 Feb. 26, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter [1826] March 17, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison [1826 March 21], ALS (Box 2)
- Robert Lewis to his sister Betty (Lewis) Carter 1826 May 9, Typescript (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his sister Eleanor C. L. Brown 1826 May 22, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Mary Jane Harrison 1826 June 1, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1826 June 22, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary Jane Harrison 1826 June 30, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1826 July, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Rev. William Monore 1826 Aug. 4, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Rev. Jacob B. Crist 1826 Oct., ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1826 Nov. 2, ALS (Box 2)
- Margaret F. Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1826 Nov. 5, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Thomas [?] [ ca. 1826], AL (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to [?] [ ca. 1826-1827], 2 AL (fragments) 1 AL (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to [?] 1827 Jan. 8, AL (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1827 Jan. 26, ALS (Box 2)
- George Tucker to his mother-in-law Betty (Lewis) Carter 1827 Feb. 7, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1827 Feb. 9, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1827 Feb. 26, ALS (Box 2)
- Maria Mc. Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1827 April 13, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1827 March 10, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1827 March 31, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Mary Jane Harrison 1827 March 31, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1827 April 17, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1827 April 23, ALS (Box 2)
- George Tucker to Maria R. F. Tucker 1827 Aug. 24, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1827 Sept. 20; Nov. 4 & 28, 3 ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1827 May 17, 2 ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1827 May 31, ALS (Box 2)
- Robert Lewis to his sister Betty (Lewis) Carter 1827 July 15, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1827 July 14, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1827 Dec. 24, ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1828 Jan. 12, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1828 Jan. 19, ALS (Box 2)
- John Temple to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1828 Jan. 31, ALS (Box 2)
- Edward Tiffin Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1828 Feb. 1 & 4, 2 ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1828 March 11, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1828 March 16; April 6, 2 ALS (Box 2)
- Lawrence Fielding Carter to his mother Betty (Lewis) Carter 1828 April 22, ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1828 April 23, ALS (Box 2)
- Gessner Harrison to Dr. Peachey Harrison 1828 April 27, ALS (Box 2)
- Ellen L. Orr to Betty (Lewis) Carter 1828 April 28, ALS (Box 2)
- [Edward Tiffin Harrison] to [Gessner Harrison] 1828 April, AL (Box 2)
- Maria Mc. Harrison to Edward Tiffin Harrison 1828 May 4, ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. Peachey Harrison to Gessner Harrison 1828 May 16, ALS (Box 2)